{"posts":[{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"where can we view our final marks","answers":[{"text":"get a transcript via myunsw","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"will we be receiving feedback from our exams and assignments i can see the assignment marks in webcms but feedback would be good and as far as i can tell we haven t received our specific exam mark let alone any feedback from it thanks","answers":[{"text":"you can see the marking output from your assignments by going to the assignment x submission page and clicking collect submission no doubt this will trigger a rash of complaints along the lines of i deserved more marks you should be able to work out your scaled exam mark from finalmark labs quizzes assign1 assign2 blogging note that exam marks were heavily scaled up can t fail too many even if they deserve it because they failed to demonstrate programming competence or knowledge of computer systems","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi is it normal for us to be unable to view our assignment 1 marks still thanks","answers":[{"text":"yet another comp1521 stuff up now fixed","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"most likely tomorrow or by 8th dec","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i have received an le for final mark but i have finished all the course work and done the exams i would like to have my marks rechecked","answers":[{"text":"everyone has le wait until dec 8th or so","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"if marks are estimated to be finalised on 8th december will supplementary exams still be hosted around 9th of december","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi is the lab mark finalized i still cannot see the practical lab mark","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi if we still don t have our assignment marks yet should we email our tutor or wait a few more days","answers":[{"text":"wait all of your tutors have gone away for summer so they won t be marking them the plan is to finish comp1521 off by late next week","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i still have not got my grade for assignment 1 and assignment 2 it is showing n a in my grades web page anyone has the same case","answers":[{"text":"hi try clicking the arrow box next to n a on your sturec for assignment 2 if it has been marked you will be able to see a mark on the submission collection","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks i find it it is so great","theta":1,"count":0}],{"text":"everyone is in the same boat don t expect to see any marks before november 20","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"ok thanks","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"given it is now approaching 11 weeks since the first assignment was submitted and 6 weeks since the second i can t see how this can be deemed acceptable","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i agree this is well bellow the acceptable standard it shows a failure of not just planning but of the course management and those responsible for checking courses are running properly and intervene when nessesary","theta":1,"count":0}],[{"text":"actually the 2nd assignment for some is out i have mine it depends on whether the tutors have marked it or not since the tutors also have exams you might be lucky to get ur ass2 mark","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i was just wondering if we would still get a mark for keeping a consistent blog seeing as there isn t a field for it in the grades section","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi will the mark of le eventually change to something else and around what time would that happen if it does thanks","answers":[{"text":"it will change to a proper mark grade a couple of days after we submit the marks to unsw i m expecting this to happen around december 3 or 4","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i was unable to attend the final due to medical reasons will the supplementary be of equal difficulty to the standard final or do they increase the difficulty due to the extra time those who take the supplementary exam have","answers":[{"text":"alright thank you","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"it s impossible to make something of equal difficulty but there s no intention to make it harder","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"or easier","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"could you tell me how i can query my lab results because when i query the results on the web page it is still blank thank you","answers":[{"text":"once the exam in my pg course is over i ll be working full time on the marking backlog","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"if i pass 7 10 test in the q3 do i get some of the mark of it thanks","answers":[{"text":"it said on the exam that you could get partial marks for programming questions i think it said the same thing in the 17s2 sample exam read it again","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"when do we have the supplementary exam timetable","answers":[{"text":"supps will be in december around the 9th but they re only available for people who did not sit the exam today and have a good reason for not doing so","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"but outline says there are other ways which can gain the chance for supplementary exam","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"yes yes there s the close to pass and so on clause it s still around december 9 and i won t know who s eligible for at least two weeks","theta":1,"count":0}]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"if i my final mark is in the range 47 finalmark lt 50 or 20 exammark lt 24 and finalmark 50 when can i take the supplementary exam","answers":[{"text":"or less precisely sometime around december 9","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"december 9","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi for the float question on the exam i couldn t calculate the fractions since bc doesn t do fractions and i couldn t figure out how to use xcalc for fractions so i left the fractions unsimplified will i be penalized for this thanks","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi there may i ask what is the command if we want to use qtspim in the exam is it qtspim main s or qtspim exe s","answers":[{"text":"qtspim after that load exe s to qtspim","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks a lot jiaxuan","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hey sir i have spent hours on sample exam 4 q1 but still dont know whats wrong with my program could i have the solution to it thanks","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"are we allowed to create files to test out theory questions in final exam","answers":[{"text":"yes","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"can we use man 7 ascii in writing section","answers":[{"text":"yes","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"when i run check command i got following error and i can not fighre out why running make just in case you haven t make nothing to be done for all ok couldn t make q2 q2 is not executable can i get some idea why that happen thank you in advance","answers":[{"text":"i have the same problem and i do not know how to fix it please if you fixed that share it here thanks","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"no idea trying to infer from the very limited info you sent i d be guessing that you re in a directory that contains a directory called q2 but if that were the case the check script should have complained about not finding a tests directory unless there was a tests directory impossible to work out without seeing your complete environment","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"hi jas i have also tried the lab5 autotest for isk s it also does not work i wonder if because the test root has been changed and we are not able to use these autotest anymore thank you in advance","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"this has happened many times for different questions z5200681 vx4 tmp amd glass export glass 4 z5200681 comp1521 prac exams week11 04 q2 ls alhtotal 56kdrwx 3 z5200681 z5200681 4 0k nov 4 02 19 drwxr x 4 z5200681 z5200681 4 0k nov 4 01 38 rw r 1 z5200681 z5200681 206 oct 23 2017 makefile rw r 1 z5200681 z5200681 2 3k nov 4 02 19 students c rw r 1 z5200681 z5200681 296 oct 25 2017 students h rw r 1 z5200681 z5200681 6 4k nov 4 02 19 students o rwxr x 1 z5200681 z5200681 12k nov 4 02 19 stu rw r 1 z5200681 z5200681 662 oct 25 2017 stu c rw r 1 z5200681 z5200681 4 5k nov 4 02 10 stu odrwxr x 2 z5200681 z5200681 4 0k oct 11 22 07 testsz5200681 vx4 tmp amd glass export glass 4 z5200681 comp1521 prac exams week11 04 q2 check q2running make just in case you haven tmake stu is up to date okcouldn t make q2q2 is not executablez5200681 vx4 tmp amd glass export glass 4 z5200681 comp1521 prac exams week11 04 q2","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"happens for q2 in practice exam 5 also z5200681 vx4 tmp amd glass export glass 4 z5200681 comp1521 prac exams week11 05 q2 ls alhtotal 60kdrwx 3 z5200681 z5200681 4 0k nov 4 03 19 drwxr x 4 z5200681 z5200681 4 0k nov 4 02 42 rw r 1 z5200681 z5200681 290 oct 26 2017 makefile rw r 1 z5200681 z5200681 2 1k nov 4 03 19 students c rw r 1 z5200681 z5200681 303 oct 26 2017 students h rw r 1 z5200681 z5200681 2 4k nov 4 03 19 students o rwxr x 1 z5200681 z5200681 7 8k nov 4 03 19 mkstu rw r 1 z5200681 z5200681 596 oct 26 2017 mkstu c rw r 1 z5200681 z5200681 1 4k nov 4 03 19 mkstu o rwxr x 1 z5200681 z5200681 7 8k nov 4 03 19 stu rw r 1 z5200681 z5200681 593 oct 26 2017 stu c rw r 1 z5200681 z5200681 1 5k nov 4 03 16 stu odrwxr x 2 z5200681 z5200681 4 0k nov 4 03 19 testsz5200681 vx4 tmp amd glass export glass 4 z5200681 comp1521 prac exams week11 05 q2 check q2running make just in case you haven tmake nothing to be done for all okcouldn t make q2q2 is not executablez5200681 vx4 tmp amd glass export glass 4 z5200681 comp1521 prac exams week11 05 q2","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"deleted","answers":[{"text":"hi there if 0x2710 is 10000 in decimal wouldn t that imply it s in index 1 of the process address space since every page is 8kb big","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"are there files for the sample exam","answers":[{"text":"no take the solutions remove the relevant bits and try to re create them","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"deleted","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"and are we allowed to use the terminal while answering questions 4 to 12 cheers harold","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"no","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"is that outlined somewhere in the exam spec and given that s the case how do we use submit","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"obviously there will also be check and submit","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i m sorry but i am strugglingto find where a distinction has been made between materials accessible for questions1 3 and 4 12 in the exam information if you could please point me in the right direction to find such a distinction in the exam specification it would be greatly appreciated regards harold","theta":1,"count":0}],[{"text":"how do we access check and submit without the terminal or do you mean we can t use the specific terminal application on the cse computers but we get the exam environment shell","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"when did i say that you would not have a terminal the setup is the same as what you had in the week 11 lab","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"sorry when harold asked are we allowed to use the terminal while answering questions 4 to 12 and you said no i interpreted that as us not being able to use the terminal","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]]]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hey sir why 100000 cannoy be presented by either binary system or hexdecimal system thanks","answers":[{"text":"is it because it is a 16 bit sting instead of 32 bit sting which we usually use","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"the above answers would make sense if the context was 16 bit ints whose maximum value is 65535 the question clearly says that we re dealing with 16 bit quantities give a representation for each of the following decimal values in 16 bit twos complement bit strings","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"exit or exit what is the main difference between exit and exit and when do we use them","answers":[{"text":"void exit int status terminates current process triggers any functions registered as lt large gt atexit lt large gt flushes stdio buffers closes open lt large gt file lt large gt s then behaves like lt large gt exit lt large gt this is from lec slides","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"if for some reason someone wanted to print out an ascii value which was lt 0 or gt 127 using printf c 1 or 128 what do we recognise that symbol or character as just an undefined symbol","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"are lab marks released not sure if it is only me didn t get the mark result it is still 10","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi the autotest for previous lab and and every prac exam q2 does not work now is there any way that we can access the autotest or can it be fixed thank you in advanceeeeee","answers":[{"text":"i assume you mean that check has stopped working the check script is nothing magical it ssimply runs all of the tests in the relevant tests directory you can run individual tests via e g sh tests 1 sh in the directory where the appropriate code and the tests are located","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"can we use man 2 to search for functions during the exam thanks","answers":[{"text":"yes you can access man pages most things you d want to find for this course would be in man 2 3 and 7","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"will the solutions for practice exams be uploaded thanks","answers":[{"text":"no","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"are the correct answers to the quizzes available anywhere","answers":[{"text":"q1 d b c c q2 e b b e q3 b b b a q4 b b d b q5 c a d c q6 b d c b","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"is wsn security gonna be assessed","answers":[{"text":"no","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i ve heard a lot of people had trouble with mips in the practice exam and still aren t confident programming in it so i made a bunch of practice exercises for people to use to make sure they get some practice doing a variety of programming tasks in mips many of them are similar to exercises you may have done in comp1511 you can access the page here http z5214348 web cse unsw edu au prac notes all of the mips exercises i ve made available have 10 autotests you can run using check similar to how we do for lab exercises and have starting code usually just a main function skeleton or a simple loop to iterate through an array and print out values i also made a simple utility to run mips code called run which is included in the code zip in each practice exercise it s just a basic c program which will either run 1521 spim file lt file gt if on a cse machine or spim file lt file gt if on your home computer assuming it can find the executable also it will default to running exe s or main s files if it can find them in the current directory or you can pass in a mips file as the first argument run lt mips file gt i hope that some of you find these exercises useful i ll be posting more up as the week goes by it takes me a while to sort out the autotests if there is a high demand for them then i ll also post sample solutions for all of the exercises i can kind regards and happy studying callum avery","answers":[{"text":"hi when i try to run the check main s command for the question it tell me bash check command not found so can i have some idea about how can i run the test check main s bash check command not found thank you in advance","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"the check tool is a tool which is in the cs1521 bin in order to use this you need to be running a 1521 subshell run 1521 by itself in a cse environment shell and then the check command should work","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"hey sorry i m getting a slightly different problem usage home cs1521 bin check q1 q2 q3 not sure how to fix this thanks for such a great resource","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"dw i fixed it i needed to use the check old command","theta":1,"count":0}]]],{"text":"excellent work i thoroughly endorse these","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"qtspim error attempt to execute non instruction at address i am only getting this issue on the cse computers the way i use qtspim is type qtspim in command line wait for it to open up file gt load file i get this issue no matter which mips file i am using even for code that is correct i know it s correct because when i run the tests i pass all of them what s even more strange is that qtspim works fine on my own computer if i load the same file the same way qtspim works properly and does not show me this error why doesn t it work on the cse computers also i tried looking for the instruction at the address shown but it s no where to be found on the page anyone know why this may be happening","answers":[{"text":"have you tried single stepping the code to find out where it jumps to 0x004005a8","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"hi john thank you for replying yes it just shows the error straight away how i did it just then right click desktop gt applications gt other gt qtspim gt file gt load file gt pick an exe s file gt click on the single step button on the menu i tried putting a break point on the second instruction of the page before clicking on single step and it still comes up with the error am really confused","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"what value is showing in the pc register before and after you load the program","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"before when i first open qtspim after loading the file after i try to run the program","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"can t work it out from here email me exe s what does the command which qtspim show","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"during the exam can we make another gedit to test the some of the theory questions on terminal","answers":[{"text":"you can open as many xterm s and gedit s as you like during the exam","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"you should be able to open up more than one terminal in the exam environment and also gedit","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"can we express that answer with 0xfffb","answers":[{"text":"yes","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"will solutions for the sample exam questions be released if so when and where","answers":[{"text":"released","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"in solution it says that for char type there are 1 byte and 3 bytes padding i am confused about what is 3 bytes padding thanks a lot","answers":[{"text":"the padding ensures that uoc done is aligned to a 4 byte boundary if status happened to be at offset 40 from the start of the record and you simply allocated 1 byte for the field then uoc done would be located at offset 41 this does not produce a valid address for an int value","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"will we have access to bc in the exam","answers":[{"text":"yes","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"what is the compiling flag in the final exam gcc wall werror std gnu99 o or gcc wall werror std c99 o","answers":[{"text":"hadn t decided which would you prefer","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"the one where you can specify the int in a for loop","theta":1,"count":0}],[{"text":"gnu99 would be better","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i was wondering whether 0 is counted as a character in mips i ve attempted q1 of practice test 3 and below is what happens my code successfully converts the string to lower case however there are errors thrown am i supposed to be using a string for 0 instead","answers":[{"text":"possibly try nul or just a 0 the null terminator maps to a 0 ascii value","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i ve tried both and they don t work but thanks","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"loading 0 in does work did you load as an integer rather than enclosed in quotes eg li t0 0 then append to the dest array using sb alternatively you should be able to load the null terminator from the src string in the same way as all the other chars and save it in the dest string let me know if that still isn t working as it might be a separate issue","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks i was using just 0 but turns out a typo had caused the bad address issue","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"deleted","answers":[{"text":"in any case i m working on the auto testing for ass2 now","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"why does it matter i e how does knowing your assignment marks make any difference to your exam preparation where you should always be trying to get 100 anyway","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"of course it is for me sometimes just keep worrying about it cos didnt do well in assignments thanks for ur advice","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi jas will solutions answers for the practice exams available be released thank you","answers":[{"text":"this week oct 22 26","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi jas can we have a little more sample exam such as the 18s1 one even without file and test really want to get some more information about the final exam thank you in advance","answers":[{"text":"the sample and 17s2 exams are quite representative enough of comp1521 exams not to mention the practice prac exam questions","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi are we allowed to use python in the final exam to help us convert hex to binary","answers":[{"text":"python is not available in the exam environment","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i wanna redo the sample exam in this case how to download the test file in vlab or i have to copy and paste those files one by one thanks","answers":[{"text":"if i have time in the next week i ll make an exam tar file available for the sample exam in the meantime copy and paste the files one by one","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"the problem i met is that for example in q1 i copied 1 exe and 1 sh then gave command exe array s but nothing came out","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"try running 1521 exe array s exe is in the cs1521 bin directory so in order to run it you need to be running a 1521 subshell","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi is there a possibility the final exam will ask us to write code for a stack or queue implementation thanks","answers":[{"text":"thanks for the suggestion there was always a possibility of this","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i was really struggled doing sample exam so just wanna know when will the solutions be realesd wihch whould be really helpful for students like me and btw when will we get our assignment feedback thanks","answers":[{"text":"no solutions will be released for the prac exam just reading solutions doesn t help so much ask your tutor to go through the process of developing the solution in tutes this week this is far more useful assignment marks should be done by week 13","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi will the questions in the practice lab test be released if we want to redo them thanks","answers":[{"text":"have a look under sample exams","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i have a question about mips how to show the if string i 0 in mips or say in mips how to show the 0 i write it as beq s0 0 else bne s0 0 if ps the string i is in s0 but it is showing wrong please help","answers":[{"text":"use the int constant 0 rather than the char 0 for representing the nul char in this case the instruction is assuming that the first two operands are registers since you happen to have a register that always contains the value 0 you could that 0","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi there i am wondering what the answer for q1 of quiz 6 is","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i have an exam on the morning of november 5th that clashes with the final for this class how should i proceed","answers":[{"text":"there is both a morning and afternoon exam session for comp1521 attend the afternoon session of the comp1521 exam we ll be putting up a timeslot selection page soon and we know about all of the clashes already","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i m just enquiring about the overall view of the use of the goto function for the assignment usually i would avoid it but it makes my code a lot cleaner to view is the goto function actually allowed to be used in 1521 thanks","answers":[{"text":"beware of dinosaurs https xkcd com 292","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i d be very very careful in thinking a goto would be useful here prefer other control flow mechanisms first but if it comes down to it and you re absolutely dying without it sure be very very very clear about what you re doing with it more so than you usually would","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i remember from my comp1511 exam there was a supplied vimrc file but i wasted too much time fiddling around with the settings to get it the way that i wanted i can never remember the different set syntax for tab spacing and colour settings would it be possible to get a copy of this file or the location of an example of this file so that i can practise tweaking it thanks","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi there i was just wondering if it would be at all possible to get some form of worked solutions to any of the questions specifically practical q s in the past exams posted i understand if this is not able to be done but i think many of us would really appreciate being able to check our attempts and improve our understanding approach through having an idea of what would be expected as sufficient answers otherwise any recommendations for ways to enhance our practical ability would be much appreciated as i am not sure where to find questions to practice and review my understanding of the content in the course thanks a lot","answers":[{"text":"i was just wondering if it would be at all possible to get some form of worked solutions to any of the questions specifically practical q s in the past exams posted see the notice i posted this morning the answer is yes i thought all of the theory exercises were already visible apparently not but now they are i am not sure where to find questions to practice any of the recommended texts garica molina ullman widom silberschatz korth will have a whole bunch of exercises and you may be able to find answers and there are the exercises i did or at least noted in lectures","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"can we run code to deal with essay questions in final thanks a lot","answers":[{"text":"yes","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi are there going to be some autotests released soon from assignment 2 spec for correct performance measured by auto testing on a range of test cases some of which will be provided for you to test your code as you write it","answers":[{"text":"after thinking about it and seeing some of the questions on the forum it s clear that giving you an auto testing framework is never going to work the chances of your mymysh running in your environment producing the same output as our expected output is almost zero for us running it in our test environment is no problem because the environment is completely controlled by us however i ll put up some examples of the kinds of tests we ll be using and the kinds of expected output for each you can run them in your own directory but will have to interpret them relative to your environment","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks jas for the practice practical lab test this week do we get access to the mips cheat sheet","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"yes","theta":1,"count":0}]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hey sir when will we get feedback from assignment 1","answers":[{"text":"maybe this week","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi how can we change to the home directory to make a file thanks","answers":[{"text":"you don t need to change to the home directory find the full path name of the home directory and then concatenate mymysh history to it to get a complete filename","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"will the child process stop after executing the execve function when i want to print something after the execve function it seems nothing can be printed thanks a lot","answers":[{"text":"if execve succeeds then it won t return to the code after it is called what it is doing is basically replacing the currently executing program with another program to run the child process will therefore exit from its new program rather than the one it was running before exec was called if you can print anything after execve you can assume that execve failed","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"so if we want to print something after execve should we look through the command history and then determine if we need to print something","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi sir i ve sent you an email but haven t gotten a reply back and it s been a few days it s quite urgent so i was wondering if you could please check it thankyou so much for your time","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi what is the use of command number in main function what is the command to clear the command history in that file every time when i use the cs1521 bin mymysh and show the command history and there exists 8 commands and when i close the terminal and open it again there are still 8 commands in history and what i typed before does not exist thanks","answers":[{"text":"if you want to clear the command history file simply remove it rm mymysh history it sounds like you re not writing the history properly when you exit mymysh","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"but i use the cs1521 bin mymysh to test it seems that it cannot be removed","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"cs1521 bin mymysh uses your mymysh history if you remove that file and the hsitory doesn t go away then there s something wrong with your initcommandhistory","theta":1,"count":0}]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i am still confused about what should we initialise in initcommandhistory the struct that needs to use have all been initialised above that function thanks","answers":[{"text":"the struct might exist but what values does it contain maybe you need to fill it up from the history file","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"will there be solutions for the wk 7 tutorial questions","answers":[{"text":"there will be solutions to all tutorial questions when i get some time to copy them across","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi about the 17s2 sample final exam where can i find the related files like in q1 there should be files like array s main s and etc where can i access them and will the answer be provided note i can access find the files for 17s2 final exam but for not for the sample exam thanks","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi question about the quiz mark i remembered that i submitted the quiz5 question but it is not shown in my marks so could you double check if my quiz 6 answer has successfully been submitted thank you","answers":[{"text":"your quiz 6 has been submitted","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i haven t uploaded the quiz 5 marks from webcms3 to sms yet","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"will the debugging lecture be recorded and uploaded","answers":[{"text":"yes i ve grabbed the video from echo360 and edited it i ll upload on thursday morning","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i am still confused about how to use the chdir function it is said in main that i should put a const str as an argument but i don t know what should this string be thanks a lot","answers":[{"text":"the pathname of the directory you want to change to e g home cs1521","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi my compiler seems to be stuck in dcc even though my makefile specifies gcc is there any way i can fix this here is a screenshot of what that looks like using c99 throws a lot more errors also is there any way i can get past the error shown here because i m calling addtocommandhistory in init i m setting the struct in addtocommandhistory while i ve initalised the strut in init thanks in advance","answers":[{"text":"are you using commandhistory anywhere else in your code","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"yes i m writing the contents of commandhistory into the history file in savecommandhistory and i m also printing from commandhistory in showcommandhistory","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"the error message says that you re not using it in the function initcommandhistory if you ve moved the definition of commandhistory into this function then put it back outside like it was in the supplied code if the original definition is still there outside any function get rid of your above definition your initialiser is not correct in any case it s not an array of int values","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you i ve gotten rid of my above definition and my compiler is back to gcc i have no clue why it went to dcc yesterday","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi about the 17s2 sample final exam where can i find the related files like in q1 there should be files like array s main s and etc where can i access them and will the answer be provided note i can only find the files for 17s2 final exam but for not the sample exam thanks","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i was just wondering if there will be more than one time slot for the final exam or if there is only one session also will these be posted on webcms or will they get updated to the exam time table on myunsw for us to check thanks a lot","answers":[{"text":"in the past there have been two exams one in the morning and one if the afternoon of the same day jas will ask for an requests and if you don t give one you will be randomly assigned the final timetable will be posted on webcms and you will be emailed","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"regarding the pwd functionality is it safe to assume it will not be longer than maxline answer to this is probably no if not are we allowed to use the posix 1 2001 standard change referenced in the man to dynamically create the string so long as we free it as an extension to the posix 1 2001 standard glibc s getcwd allocates the buffer dynamically using malloc 3 if buf is null in this case the allocated buffer has the length size unless size is zero when buf is allocated as big as necessary the caller should free 3 the returned buffer","answers":[{"text":"you can use the posix extension we ll be running it with the appropriate library","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi jas is there a way to see what s been written in our home mymysh history thanks","answers":[{"text":"just cat the file or open it in a text editor","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi jas how should i think of handle history substitution in the main and how it works","answers":[{"text":"look at the examples try it out on the reference solution","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"another question is about glob function i am confused about the first parameter pattern and i had checked man glob that it said matching pattern according to the rules used by the shell what s this parameter means","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"try some examples with the real shell e g echo c to see how filename pattern matching works","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"so can i use ass2 for the first parameter of glob or argv else","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"have a look at man 7 glob for what can be given as the first parameter","theta":1,"count":0}],[{"text":"sure as the first parameter to glob but it s unlikely to match anything so the result returned from glob would be the single string ass2","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"how should i find the right command line in the stdin by using loop cause i wanna deal with handle history substitution this part","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"history substitution and glob are for different parts of the shell if a input needs history substitution it should be felt with first and no globbing or redirecting should be done","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi jas regarding to the cleancommandhisotry function i am a little bit confused and would like some clarification since you have declared commandhistory as a global variable already does this mean we don t need to malloc memory to it anymore since any changes to it will be kept for example if we call addtocommandhistory cmdline seqno it will still remain its changes after this function finishes so do we still need cleancommandhisotry but maybe my understanding towards global variable is wrong looking forward to the response cheers","answers":[{"text":"if you look carefully at the historyentry data structure you ll see that the comandline field is a pointer not a buffer so it needs tp be malloc d and cleaned you re barking up the wrong tree with your global variable theory","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"oh i see thank you for the clarification also i just noticed that for the history substitution if we type something in bash like e it will be replaced by exit h will be replaced by history and so on do we need to take this feature into consideration","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"mymysh isn t bash only implemt whats in the spec","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"ok thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"why this information occur when i sign in the vlab","answers":[{"text":"have you got two vlab windows open","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi jas how do we recovered our deleted files or directory in unix","answers":[{"text":"there s a command called tkrestore that can get them from the latest backup which probably happened early in the morning it s described on the cse taggi if you ve made more changes since then then you ve lost it","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi jas would you mind uploading the lecture note of week 9 network the lecture note on week 8 appears to be about network but they are actually about concurrency if we click in thank you very much","answers":[{"text":"i m not sure why you say the lecture note on week 8 appears to be about network they may have had the old networks slides attached there last week but i m pretty sure i changed them on friday maybe earlier to the new concurrency slides in any case i m still working on the week 09 slides i ll post them when they re in better shape maybe you re talking about the course notes they re mislabelled i ll fix them now","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"oh yes i was talking about the labels thank you very much","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"are the lecture slides down i get access forbidden","answers":[{"text":"i think i ve fixed them","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"will we go over the bank example with semaphores in the next lecture the recording just cut out just as jas was saying you can use semaphores to solve the producer consumer problem or will it be on the recording that isn t on echo","answers":[{"text":"come to think of it i didn t do that exercise i looked at the producer consumer example i ll do the bank example tomorrow","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"it s on my recording which i ll upload to youtube tomorrow wed morning","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"are the quizes changed to one attempt only since previous quizes allows multiple attempts","answers":[{"text":"not intentionally i ve fixed it","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"deleted","answers":[{"text":"i m not sure of the context but often indexes are in the range 0 npages 1","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"how does fork know which is the parent in order to set the return value in the child to 0 at the moment it seems like fork in the parent creates a duplicate and gets the pid of the child it created but how does the recently created child know that it isn t a parent and then execute the fork as well instead of just putting 0 into the pid cheers","answers":[{"text":"the child gets a return value of 0 from fork that s how it knows it s not the parent","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi robert i m not sure if this answers your question or not let me know if anything is still unclear when we use the fork function the operating system creates a new process for us that is a fairly exact copy of the parent the new process has its own address space think virtual memory that we just did in the labs but initially it copies the parent s address space it assigns this new process a pid the parent and the child will then run as separate processes from the fork the parent gets a return value the os hands it the pid of the new process child just created in the child we also return from fork even though technically the child didn t exist when the fork was called and the os hands the child process 0 as the return value if we want to check if it s the parent or child we simply check if the return value from fork was 0 or something else","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"yeah that helps thanks all i was missing is that the os gives the 2 processes their fork return values thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"a bit confusion about failed system call in quiz 4 question 1 i tried that on my own machine of course i don t have file xyz neither access it as other user it prints no such file or directory my question is which expression prints out this error it seems exit 1 made this happen also i still have question about memory management one page size and one frame size are equal why should we have to calculate off set won t one page be loaded exactly to the first address of one frame i know this seems a bit fall behind the lecture but thanks in advance","answers":[{"text":"which expression prints out this error perror null prints the error message it knows what to print based on the current value of the global variable errno which is set by any failing system call why should we have to calculate off set because addresses can be anywhere at the start of a page at the end of a page somewhere in the middle of a page virtual memory tells us which frame contains the address we asked for the offset tells us whereabouts in the page the address is located","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"has quiz 4 closed i read the time wrong and assumed it was due at midnight","answers":[{"text":"in the final exam i read the question wrong no second chance fortunately this isn t the final exam so i extended the deadline to midnight","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i can t see my grades for recent labs and my mark for the last quiz","answers":[{"text":"ask your tutor about lab grades i ll be posting the marks for the quiz 3 later today needs some fiddling","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"fixed","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i am doing the lab06 and i am confused about the error in the terminal so what wrong in here it said runtime error illegal array pointer or other operation and stopped in main argc 2","answers":[{"text":"i don t know what your functions do exactly but i d be very surprised if they returned a floating point number your printf format string is now correct think about what kind of values are being printed in each column and choose an appropriate format for each hint most are strings","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"please help after 48 hours of debugging and 2 re writes i am v frustrated i know that offsetting into a 2d array x y the offset is found by x number of columns y now when offsetting into the bigstring array should we be using the number of columns as nscols or biglength running my code through qtspim i notice that if we use nscols then on many of the loops the offset goes from for e g 0 9 and then 9000 or 1000 depending on whatever nscols is where as if i were to use number of columns as biglength then it goes from 0 9 to 10 which seems more natural and correct atm my code compiles and runs but it s just printing what i assume to be bunch of blank spaces as the curser flips about rapidly for a short while and then then the program terminates in success though not failure any assistance to the above question or the nature of my output would be greatly appreciated","answers":[{"text":"the length in bytes of a row in bigstring is 9 1 100 9 because each bigchar is a 9x9 array 1 for the single column after each bigchar 100 because there is space for 100 bigchars in bigstring nscols is an unfortunate choice of name it is actually a count of the total bytes in bigstring","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"so changing nscols to 1000 is the way to go","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"probably not that may have other consequences easiest to just use the constant 1000 is computing byte offsets within bigstring or if you don t want people accusing you of using magic numbers define a new constant give it a sensible name and use that","theta":1,"count":0}],[{"text":"you won t need to change it unless there is a specific issue which you shouldn t encounter","theta":1,"count":0}]],{"text":"the maximum columns in bigstring is nscols since bigstring nrows nscols nscols isn t used as a point of comparison for loops rows lt nscols but ndcols is clear your head a bit and make sure you re not mixing the 2 seems like your registers are being changed so make sure they are holding the values you expect them to your output issue would be dependent upon the validity of your arrays so that may be causing issues there","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i keep getting this error in qtspim instruction references undefined symbol at 0x00400014 0x00400014 0x0c000000 jal 0x00000000 main 188 jal main edit yep ok","answers":[{"text":"this is the default address of main until a file containing main is loaded into qtspim load your exe s file","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"you are loading your file into qtspim right","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"when i try to run my code it become a full white board like this what s wrong thx","answers":[{"text":"your arrays could be empty so printing our or the delay function is taking forever to show something so comment that out for now if the arrays are not containing the expect character value make sure your formulas are correct and registers are holding their expected value","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"if i use t0 to represent the address of an array and store a value into the array can i use t0 later to represent something else change it to other meanings","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"presuming that t0 is not used in that loop then sure make sure you remember temporary registers can be changed after a function is called","theta":1,"count":0}]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi may i know what does this means tt","answers":[{"text":"something goes wrong when the program counter is at 0x00400364 go into qtspim and check what happens in that area from a guess it has something to do with bigstring row col but common issues seem to be checking your array offset formulas are correct checking your registers are holding the correct values or something else so could be going out of the bigstring array","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"is it right to run the code such 1521 spim file exe s hello world when i try to run that way it becomes like below and it cannot stop","answers":[{"text":"use this instead 1521 spim file exe s hello world with quotes currently your program is ignoring world so this error hasn t got anything to do with having multiple words the error you have is because you are trying to access a word int without 4 byte alignment look at any loops you have that access arrays of ints or any arrays of chars that are accessed with lw instead of the correct lb","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"why should there is lt gwmw class ginger module highlighter mistake anim ginger module highlighter mistake type 1 id gwmw 15357847692412475371398 gt lb lt gwmw gt since and are all values","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"because chars are only one byte in size while lw moves 4 bytes and that causes alignment errors","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i have checked all the place that i use lw it is only used when i get the value from hash define there is still exception5 error when i try to run the code","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"which hash define you having issues with","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"sorry there is no problem with hash define it just runs exception5 error infinitely address error in store dylan says look at any loops you have that access arrays of ints or any arrays of chars that are accessed with lw instead of the correct lb but i have checked there is no problem","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i personally find the lt gwmw impossible to read presuming it is a lw lb issue are you using lw when appropriate for your global variables defines so lw t0 nrows otherwise i can t understand your problem sorry","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi how do i pass a string with more than one word in qtspim running 1521 spim file exe s two words works fine in the terminal but when i try to pass two words into the run parameters in qtspim it gives me the only letters and spaces are allowed in the string error is there something wrong on my end or is there something different i have to do within qtspim","answers":[{"text":"what machine are you running qtspim on does it work for just one word","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"yes it works with one word but not one word in quotation marks so it works for hello but not hello or hello world i m running it through vlab on my mac","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"if it works for two words in the terminal that s fine we won t be testing your code in qtspim","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"further on this point i can run my program fine in a terminal but there seems to be a bug when i have a space in the input like below scroll s why not as qtspim or mars don t support an input like above it makes it extremely difficult to debug the issue using only the terminal is there any other approaches i can take to try and fix this below is an example ignore the extra s they are there for troubleshooting of what i am trying to resolve thanks","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i told you in lectures that you can get around the qtspim problem by defining a constant string and using that instead of getting the string from argv 1 you ll need to tweak your main program a bit to accomplish this but at least you can debug note that spim itself has some crude debugging run spim without any args and type help","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i was trying to use s8 but always get this error when clean the stack i m really confused about how to fix it","answers":[{"text":"here s where it gets weird there technically is a s8 register and it s the same as the fp register if you don t use the fp register at all you get a free save register in practice it s not done often","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi the save registers go from s0 to s7 you ll need to use a different register name check the spim instruction set summary here https webcms3 cse unsw edu au comp1521 18s2 reso","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"deleted","answers":[{"text":"https cgi cse unsw edu au cs1521 18s2 docs spim php","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"save registers only go from 0 7 so s9 does not exist as a register name","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi whenever i try to run spim on vlab i always get the message bash spim command not found how can i fix this","answers":[{"text":"try the command 1521 spim","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"in the assignment 1 template i got global variable is given the value 9000 to hold with a description that it s the number of columns in bigstring matrix with the equation nrows maxchars chrsize 1 but wouldn t give this the total bytes for bigstring the max chars atm is 100 meaning 100 letters can be printed chrsize is the width and height of a bigletter which is 9 each bigletter also gets 1 column of spacing meaning that the total number of columns in bigstring should be maxchars chrsize 1 100 9 1 1000 why did nrows get put in there too also bigstring is given 81000 bytes because it s nrows nscols","answers":[{"text":"each column has 9 nrows rows you re right that nscols isn t necessary but since it gave more than enough memory we left it unchanged","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"are we supposed to be able to have multiple attempts at quiz 4 like the other quizzes i can t change my answers after submission","answers":[{"text":"i forgot to check a box now you should be able to resubmit","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"should we submit the file with comment delay function s file or not if we submit the file with the delay function should we set a suitable display speed","answers":[{"text":"leave the delay function in place we don t care what speed you set it to","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i m a bit confused about align i always get error unaligned address i know that i should align with 4 but in the string every element only take one byte so for alignment i still need to time 4 when i calculate the address in a string","answers":[{"text":"if you use lw rather than lb to try and load a char from memory that would cause your error","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"oh yeah i got it thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi how can i pass in arguments using qtspim when i type qtspim file exe s hello it said cannot open file hello also if i type spim file exe s hello it shows this write to unused memory mapped io address 0xffffffffc what does this mean thanks for any help","answers":[{"text":"for unused memory mapped io address 0xffffffffc have a look at your stack frame set ups and tear downs qtspim is opened with qtspim file ie just a list of file names to set arguments go to simulator gt run parameters then to the send box","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi regarding to the ass1 code where does this t1 come from in the code provided i believe you want this register as ch but isn t ch stored in s2 but t1 can you please have a look at it thank you very much","answers":[{"text":"do you have the right version of scroll s i just checked version in assign1 zip and it correctly has sb t1 t0 for that line","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"oh yes i have the wrong version i have changed it back thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hello in show display function where is the first element display 0 0 stored thanks","answers":[{"text":"the display array is stored in the data section and must be loaded with la t display","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"can i drop 1521 and still get my fee back now","answers":[{"text":"census date is friday so yes but please talk to your tutor about why","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi for the scroll if you do hello amp it will not show hello amp but for the exe s it will show hello no amp also if do hello hello it will not show for scroll but for exe s it will show hello why","answers":[{"text":"scroll only shows a sentence if the whole sentence can be displayed only uppercase and lowercase letters and spaces can be displayed so hello amp should not display anything scroll hello hello and 1521 spim exe s hello hello should both print hello hello","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"is there a way to run scroll s without using qtspim i d like to see what the code actually prints in the real console window but i don t know how to pass arguments when using spim","answers":[{"text":"on a cse terminal the command is 1521 spim file exe s hello world","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank so much","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i am confused with the 3d array s offset i get offset which rowsize colsize rowindex colsize colindex but im not sure this is correct could you please help me get this offset thank you","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi just wondering where does this t1 come from in the code provided i believe you want this register as ch but isn t ch stored in s2 but t1 can you please have a look at it thank you very much","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi jas just wondering where the youtube lecture videos for week 5 are thanks","answers":[{"text":"there won t be any until i m in a position to copy the echo360 videos across maybe tonight but maybe not until sunday","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"which of course means they re available on echo360 right now","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i couldn t submit the files by using the given give command and there is no matrix h files in ex2","answers":[{"text":"matrix h isn t mentioned in the output you supplied where did you get the idea that it was relevant","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"how to enable syntax highlighting in vi vim like lecturer for mips","answers":[{"text":"i do it via syntax on in my vimrc","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"is there a way to enable syntax colouring for gedit i found some ways to do it but need access to the config files to add in the package and obviously that can t happen","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"on a cse computer run jashankj bin install spim style courtesy of jashank jeremy","theta":1,"count":0}]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"how to finish the main function and return 0 to imply that the program is successfully finished or executed because for the fac2 s i have computed n correctly but the problem is when the code gets to jr ra after this instruction it goes back to the line where the function fac is being called and it keeps doing this forever how to fix that i hope that what i have written explains the problem thanks","answers":[{"text":"which jump method did you use to get to fac j or jal","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"are you printing out n forever or is it just not terminating","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"my lab marks are still not appearing when webcms tries to fetch them i don t understand why this is happening i really want to view my lab marks over the course of this semester","answers":[{"text":"you don t get marks you get grades i just checked the sms database where the grades are actually stored and there are no grades although it does note that you submitted something webcms3 also tells you this have you asked your tutor when they plan to enter them","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you i will ask them dr shepherd","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"for the lecture example with the grades today we did data for allocating mark and grade space but we didn t text before the code part is that just forgetting or was there a reason to not put text cheers","answers":[{"text":"i just forgot there should always be text to introduce the code","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"when will the assignment1 come out thx","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"will lab exercises ever have answers as an example code solution","answers":[{"text":"i would like to know as well","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"usually not we haven t given solutions in the past","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"why is this so if someone had trouble with one of the exercises it would beneficial to see the answers and examples without seeing the answers after the cut off time has passed the opportunity to learn will be reduced","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"while you wait for an official answer to why it s not posted i could suggest other ways of learning you all should be working in pairs so it s highly unlikely that both of you don t know how to solve the lab nevertheless feel free to collaborate with other groups group learning is encouraged just don t blatantly copy code of course don t plagiarise during marking in week x 1 ask your tutor how to do it the tutor might not have time to explain the whole lab to you but they can at least try especially when the lab is quiet in my experience all the students were able to figure out how to do the labs i haven t seen a student in my classes in previous years that never solved the labs so don t stress i suspect it s not posted because jas is very busy that was his answer to not releasing the quiz answer as well","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks for your answer i appreciate people may be busy but i don t really think that is an acceptable reason not to provide answers for these types of tasks","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"in previous subjects the recorded lectures were uploaded to echo where they could be downloaded and viewed offline this cannot be done easily with youtube without either paying for a program to do this or putting our trust in a website to convert for us without adding anything malcious can these lectures also be uploaded to echo thanks","answers":[{"text":"fyi youtube dl is a open source command line utility that can grab videos from everywhere youtube included","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"afaik all of the lectures are uploaded to echo there s a link to them at the top of the lectures page","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"ok thanks i can see them there also","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"will videos for week 3 wednesday s lectures be released","answers":[{"text":"yes they will well spotted i thought i d done them and actually removed them from my laptop fortunately they re on a backup drive in my office i ll do them on monday morning when i m next at work","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"will these still be uploaded today i can t see them on echo or webcms","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"done","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks i can see them now","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"how do i get cisco anyconnect and vnc lab on my home computer","answers":[{"text":"i d try typing download anyconnect and download tigervnc into google","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i tried that but cisco keeps asking for money","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"it s also described in some of the cselearning videos windows or mac","theta":1,"count":0}],[{"text":"if you go to the cse s taggi page it gives you some links to download tigervnc and a login portal to get cisco anyconnect","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"the licence for you use anyconnect is paid for by the organisation that installed the cisco firewalls the vpn terminates on i e unsw so in this case there is no need for you to pay to use or download anyconnect go to https vpn unsw edu au using your browser and after you authenticate the firewall will automatically attempt to install anyconnect on your computer to allow you to create a vpn tunnel to the device that being said if you re using linux you may already have an cisco compatible vpn client on your machine i have been able to connect to the vpn using the built vpn client on fedora 27 without using anyconnect","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i completed quiz 2 on week02 but i cant see my grades for that quiz","answers":[{"text":"i forgot to export them from webcms3 to sms i just did that they should appear tomorrow if not remind me","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i don t know why this prints size 20 bytes instead of 24 bytes if it should be multiple of all the elements in the union it should print 24 because one double is 8 bytes someone can explain it for me please","answers":[{"text":"in this discussion there seems to be some confusion between alignment and size alignment is where the object starts in memory i e its address size is how many bytes it occupies after its starting address the size was always going to be close to 19 which is the size of the largest element in the union the precise size probably depends on the c compiler rounding it up the next multiple of 4 above 19 i e 20 would be plausible some other compilers might round it up to the next multiple of 8 if it needed to be aligned for the most restricted alignment component in the union which would be 8 because of the double if you had an array of these unions that would be a plausible scenario but this assumes that a double is 8 bytes is this guaranteed in any event these kinds of considerations point out that trying to analyse things at a level close to the machine leads to revealing machine and compiler dependencies","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"a union takes the size of its largest member i compiled your code character for character and got size was 24 although i had to use lu you might have forgotten to compiled or saved then compiled so updating your file otherwise i am not sure","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"uh the size should have been 20 and when i compile it it gives me 20 remember that the size of the union will be the largest of its members this is because it only stores enough space for only one element the largest one one way to think of it is that the address of name is the same as the address of x which is the same as the address of i in this case the largest element is the array which is 19 characters long however the size of the union is not 19 bytes because it adds a byte at the end to keep it 4 bytes aligned","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"why should it be multiple of 4 bytes is it because every computer is aligned like that in terms of union memory allocation i read somewhere that the size of union should be multiple of every element and at least the largest of the element the 2 conditions must be satisfied and a double is 8 bytes","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i think you miss understood what you read on the internet it s not multiple but alignment integers are 4 byte aligned hence since it is part of the union the union is 4 byte aligned this is not strictly necessarily but some compilers such as gcc do this alignment why didn t it align to a double tbh i m not sure if i had to take a guess it would be that since cpu registers are 32bits in a 32bit computer then accessing a double is a two instruction operation anyway","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"registers have been mentioned a lot so far during lectures do we need to know what they are or just that computers use them to do things","answers":[{"text":"if your question is do we need to understand the electronics behind their construction then the answer is no for this course you can treat them like 32 bit memory cells with names like s0 etc you can only perform operations on values that are loaded in registers so they re very important when describing computations at the machine level","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"that makes a lot of sense thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"what is this error message about","answers":[{"text":"are you compiling yourself or running make it can t find the main function does your add c file definitely have a main function at the top with no typos did add c actually compile","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i am not sure how to use spim like dr shepherd does from the terminal do i have to install anything other than spim beforehand because i keep getting bash spim command not found","answers":[{"text":"yes you need to install spim if that turns out to be too difficult use qtspim on your local machine or use vlab then spim","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i log out at unsw computer successfully but when i went home and try to open it via vlab on my laptop it tells me that i have exceeded my disk quota in my home directory and only left a terminal to me what should i do","answers":[{"text":"i use the du command to work this out du d isk u sage start at your home directory and type du s then cd into the directory with the largest disk usage and repeat keep descending the directory tree until you find a directory with a very large file remove the offending file voila or if you re not old school and if you have a window manager use the cute gui that s mentioned in the taggi","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you it did help me","theta":1,"count":0}],{"text":"https taggi cse unsw edu au faq disk quota","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}],{"text":"exceeded disk quota means the total size of files you have on your drive is higher than the allowed limit i think the command to check is rquota or something like that look for big files to delete a few students in week 1 generated very big output files in the lab by accident when doing the printing to files sometimes thats the cause","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"deleted","answers":[{"text":"a couple that we ve used as texts in the past the indispensable guide to c by davies programming problem solving and abstraction by moffat the c programming language by kernighan and ritchie","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"regarding help session on tuesdays and wednesdays should we bring our own device to law 210 amp 202","answers":[{"text":"https www learningenvironments unsw edu au space as you can see there are no computers in law so i would say definitely bring your own devices","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"will the answers to the quizzes ever be posted thanks","answers":[{"text":"maybe if i ever get some free time","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"how do i get in touch with my tutor if i don t have his email i want to send him some code to ask him for some assistance but i forgot to ask him his email in the introductory tutorial could the course admins or tutors somehow help me get in touch with him","answers":[{"text":"look on the timetable find you class click on your tutor s name and there might be an option to send them email","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"can i get lecture notes weeks 3 all in one file beforehand its easier for me to print out and jot down while lecture is held","answers":[{"text":"that requires me to write them all beforehand which is proving impossible at the moment","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"program simply gives segmentation fault when attempting to run used make add with no errors or warnings and i am unable to see where illegal memory was accessed code deleted by jas","answers":[{"text":"ellen is right the gdb debugger is useful to sort out segfaults alternatively re compile the code with dcc which does a lot of extra checking and might give an error message that helps you to debug","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi dean to find the location of the segfault you could try running the code with gdb to debug or you could try using printf statements in various places in your code to give you a clue where the program is getting up to and what function it is breaking in then try to print the specific variable values at that part of the program and see if they are what you expect them to be some things to consider when we declare a local variable the memory is uninitialised if we don t assign it it could have any value possibly quite large inside segfaults very commonly occur in arrays when we are iterating over them and access an area out of bounds think about how this relates to point 1 it s best if you don t post actual lab code on the forum test output is fine but not code files but you can either take it to a help session or ask your tutor if you need some help debugging","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"my program makes this wired symbel when it reaches a new digit i have realloc the array but doesnt work thanks in advance","answers":[{"text":"you might be picking up garbage from beyond the end of the array try re compiling with dcc or learn to use gdb or some other debugger","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"or you might have generated a weird character and stored it in the array","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i m a bit confused about bonus mark for challenge question can i get full mark if i do not do challenge and if i get a for every lab can i get full mark finally thank you","answers":[{"text":"if you get a for every lab you ll definitely get 10 10 for the labs you may even get a small bonus because we allow for students to possibly miss one lab during the semester any a marks give you an a towards your 10 10 plus an extra addition to the bonus lab mark","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"okay i got it thank you","theta":1,"count":0}],{"text":"it was indicated on the lab page as how i understood it a grade full marks a full marks bonus marks so if u do well in the normal exercises getting a s and not do the challenges you ll still end up with full marks","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"are we supposed to modify add c so that is disregards non integer arguments there is no specification for this in the lab instructions but i cannot think of another reason why test 5 is failing regards harold","answers":[{"text":"i only modified the bignum c file to let it disregard any leading non digit characters in the string pretty sure you can do it without changing the add c file","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"my bignum c worked pretty well when i tested it manually but when i tested it using cs1521 bin check add command it gave me these fails i m really confused now is there something wrong with my program or have i done any other mistakes thanks","answers":[{"text":"have a look at the out files in the test folder and run the diff commands it will give you some more info about what s going wrong in the tests","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"oh jokes i forgot to compile it to add instead i just used the a out so it didn t recognize it in the auto testing thanks a lot","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"why we change int to item i know it is convenient to change struct to stack but changing int seems meaningless and when should i use the int and when to use item","answers":[{"text":"if i wanted to define a stack of chars all i d need to do is change to typedef char item and the rest of the code would remain unchanged admittedly the whole notion of generic types is a bit lame in c","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"similar with define","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"yes","theta":1,"count":0}]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"what would be another way to determine the end of an integer array when we define an integer array whatever by malloc or simply declaration we would know its size hence we could loop through the array by index but array of integer doesn t have 0 in its end hence what could be another way to determine the case of terminating the loop for example here i would like to fill in an array with 9 this for loop runs much more times than 10 and trigged seg fault at last it seems p null is not the case that p reaches end of x what could be the correct way to exit instead of the way in comment thank you","answers":[{"text":"c doesn t have an inbuilt way of getting the size of an int array you would usually store the size of the array and use that the way you did it the first time edit the second way doesn t work because you are checking the pointer value p is not null rather than the value at x 9 which would be gotten with p you can generally set a guard at the end of an array that tells it when to stop this is how strings work with 0 in your example you are trying to use a similar technique with an int array but you will have to manually set the guard value at the end of the array null is a pointer value so you won t be able to set an int to null another way is to calculate the final address in the array and use that to terminate the loop you would have seen an example of that in lectures or tutes but that s basically the same as using array indexes","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i keep getting this error while trying to compile what s going on and how can i fix it","answers":[{"text":"put the int i declaration before the for loop eg int i for i 0 the version of c you are compiling with doesn t allow declarations inside the loop conditions","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}],{"text":"the error message tells you exactly what s wrong and even tells you how to fix it modify your makefile and add std c99 to the cflags line or define the loop variable outside the loop before the exam you need to learn how to read and act on error messages from the c compiler","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"regarding the recommended book computer systems programmer s perspective this course is not about all of the book contents from the course outline then which chapters would you suggest i read","answers":[{"text":"it s not which chapters it s which sections of chapters which should be obvious from the topics in lectures e g tuesday s lecture included unicode look up unicode in the index and go to the relevant chapter don t expect the material to be explained anything like i do in lectures it gives an alternative view the one topics you ll find nothing on in the book is mips architecture and assembler but there s plenty of material attached to the web site for mips","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hello what is the procedure if i am too unwell to attend a lab tute i can do the work from home but my lab partner would be alone and i d miss out on any participation marks i can msg my partner with shared solutions but is there something i can do to not lose that participation","answers":[{"text":"there isn t any mark for participation if that means a mark simply for being at the lab messaging your partner and working on the solution that way is participation enough","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks for the reply","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"is there a way to download all the lecture slides at once would like to annotate it and have all the slides in one file","answers":[{"text":"i ve added a link for this under the week 01 lectures it s html but you can always save as pdf if that s what you want","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"yes that is what i wanted thank you do you mind adding it for all the upcoming lectures","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"ok","theta":1,"count":0}]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"where can i see the timetable for help labs or consultations","answers":[{"text":"on the menu bar there is a help sessions tab with the timetable","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i d forgotten to put my consults on the web site i just added the times locations on the timetable page maybe that s why nobody had been coming along","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"when does the lab solution for lab01 will be available","answers":[]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hello when i try to log in using vlab i get this error server disconnected code 1006 i ve asked other people to try logging in and its working fine for them what can i do to fix this thanks","answers":[{"text":"it looks like you re using vlabgateway you shouldn t be vlabgateway is not well supported instead you should follow the instructions on taggi to set up vlab locally you ll need both software capable of talking to the unsw vpn either cisco anyconnect or openconnect and a vnc viewer like tigervnc","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"oh and i forgot to add i was using cisco anyconnect amp tigervnc before this happened i was completing the wk1 lab exercise it was when i compiled for cat3 c everything kinda froze so i closed my tigervnc upon reopening tigervnc and trying to login i couldnt log in anymore so i decided to try vlabgateway which also didnt work giving me the error server disconnected","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"it sounds to me like you ve blown a quota or otherwise made something unhappy either way say hi to one of the friendly staff in any of the 1521 labs or in a lecture break","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"oh crap i completly forgot to mention that that s exactly what happened prior to getting this error it said i had went over my quota i proceeded to delete the files that were taking up space using the rm command and then after that i was able to log in like usual but then after doing something i guess wrong while coding everything froze and then i closed vnc and reopened it only to see it not letting me log in yep i will thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]],[{"text":"have you tried rebooting your laptop","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"yep i have","theta":1,"count":0}]]],{"text":"hard to tell without seeing your entire setup can you bring your laptop to a consultation","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"unfortunately all the help sessions for this week are clashing with my lab sessions for other courses i dont think i ll be able to go to a help session until next week so at this rate i won t be able to do lab2 as well what can i do","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"what about my consultation wed 11 12 or after the lecture and why can t you do the lab exercise in the lab","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i have a tutorial during that time oh yes i will see you after the lecture then i just assumed that if it didn t let me log in at home then it wouldn t let me log in at the lab either","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"you could just use a lab workstation","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"i clearly remember making a submission of week 1 lab exercises yet on webcms it says that there is no record of the submission","answers":[{"text":"the monday 11am submissions ended up in the wrong place on the system once i move them to where they re supposed to be later today your submission will show up in the meantime demo to your tutor using the files in your directory","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"how many attempts do we get at the weekly quiz","answers":[{"text":"if understand the meaning of the allow multiple attempts button in webcms3 it should be as many as you want before the deadline if that s not the case let me know","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"i clicked on submit and it says you submitted a response to the quiz thanks it doesn t say how many i got correct or incorrect but i can change my answers and then click on submit again upon which it saves my newly chosen answers so i assume we are allowed to make multiple attempts but we aren t told if the answer is correct or not after each attempt","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"correct","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i m just wondering where exactly we do the weekly blog","answers":[{"text":"via the little speech bubble at the bottom of the webcms3 menu next to your name and next to the little graph icon that lets you check your marks","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"are the blogs that we are meant to maintain private","answers":[{"text":"i can read them the tutors can read them other students are not supposed to able to read them can you read other people s blogs","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"there s a dropdown at the bottom of a blog post in edit that lets us set privacy i assume we want to set it to course staff","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"yes","theta":1,"count":0}]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"having just come from comp1511 i have not come across makefiles before so an explanation of these would be nice especially considering they seem to create even more file o files can this be discussed in the next lecture thanks","answers":[{"text":"ok i probably should have talked about them when i was talking about the c compilation pipeline","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"how much of the course will cover c programming comp1511 was all about c programming i am wondering how much proportion is about c in this course","answers":[{"text":"thank you a lot for the replies","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i think the whole course is in c as well","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"apart from the part that deals with mips assembler around 3 4 weeks","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"will we be assessed on theory in this course if so how much of it","answers":[{"text":"there will be a final exam which tests your theory i can t say how much but i can say that past students found it reasonable and fair","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"past exams have been 50 50 programming theory i don t see any reason to change that","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"hello may i change my answer to the quiz questions before the due date of the quiz","answers":[{"text":"i think so i set the allow re submissions flag on the quiz page but since i m not a student i can t test whether it s working","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"how do we access the files to the code presented in the lecture","answers":[{"text":"they ll appear as a lecture exercises link on the lectures page as soon as i get a chance to upload them","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"where do we put our blogs can i just have my weekly thoughts in a notepad doc and give it to my tutor at the end of the semester for that glorious bonus mark","answers":[{"text":"use the webcms3 blogs in the sidebar the speech bubble takes you to your course blog","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"is there gonna be solutions for tutorials thanks","answers":[{"text":"tutorial solutions are typically released the following week","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"ok thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"where can we find the timetable of web stream lecture","answers":[{"text":"web stream lectures are just videos of the live lectures the videos will be uploaded to youtube a couple of hours after the live lecture finishes","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"oh i see thank you","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"where can i find a link to the lecture youtube channel","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"they are in the lecture tab","theta":1,"count":0}]]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"where can i find my quiz marks thanks","answers":[{"text":"after the quiz s due date is passed you ll get your quiz marks uploaded to your sturec you can see the grades link down the bottom of the menu bar","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"what am i generally expected to write in the cs1521 blog","answers":[{"text":"what you discover each week mistakes you made what you learned from them how you will do better in the future","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"in comp1511 we used edstem org as a forum to post all our questions is there one for comp1521","answers":[{"text":"you re using it now","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"typo i meant is there an edstem forum but i ll take your answer to mean no this is the forum","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"correct","theta":1,"count":0}]]]},{"intent":"forum","courseCode":"COMP1521","tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q and a","salience":0.5,"theta":1}],"question":"how long will it take for new lecture spots to open up in this course i was previously in the web lectures but i had to change my tutorial to a better day because of timing issues and now i lost my spot in the web lecture","answers":[{"text":"sometime in week 1 spots will open when the people who failed comp1511 and comp1911 get dropped from the course i ve asked the student office when they re going to do that i ll edit this message when i know the details","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"so what do i do for week 1 then do i still go to a lab or do i have to wait until i can get a lecture spot","theta":1,"count":0},[{"text":"go to a lab if there s room you can stay if not try another hopefully within a day or so some spots will open i cannot open more spots and the stupid way unsw organises enrolments means that all you can do is wait for someone to drop out","theta":1,"count":0}]]]}]}